gauravtiwari.org 2019-01-20

# Privacy Policy – Gaurav Tiwari

This document was last updated on April 6, 2018.

This  **Privacy Policy  **governs the manner in which website – gauravtiwari.org and the app [Gaurav Tiwari](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.gauravtiwari.app "Gaurav Tiwari") collect, use, maintain and disclose information collected from users (each, a “User”) of the Gaurav Tiwari (gauravtiwari.org) (hereby called, “Site”). This privacy policy applies to this website and all other products and services offered by Gaurav Tiwari (hereby called, “We”).

## Personal identification information

We may collect personal identification information from Users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when the user

  * registers with our site
  * places an order from shop
  * subscribes to the newsletter
  * fill out a form, mostly the contact and comment forms

In such cases the user may be asked for, as appropriate, name, email address.

Users may, however, visit our Site anonymously if they want. We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personally identification information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site related activities, like signing up, making comments, doing purchases etc.

## Non-personal identification information

We may collect non-personal identification information about Users whenever they interact with our Site. Non-personal identification information may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about Users means of connection to our Site, such as the operating system and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information.

## Web browser cookies

Our Site uses “cookies” to enhance User experience. User’s web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. Cookies are harmless and only used for local purposes. No user data is stored on the server or used in anyway without user’s consent.

Following services and scripts use your cookies and non-personal identification data like IP address, browser type, location and visit duration:

  * Jetpack Stats
  * Google Analytics
  * Cloudflare
  * Google Adsense
  * WordPress’ default login-register streamline (only for registered users)

User may choose to set their web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If user does so, note that some parts of the Site may not function properly.

## Advertisements

Users may find advertising or other content on our Site that link to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. We do not control the content or links that appear on these sites and are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our Site. In addition, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to our Site, is subject to that website’s own terms and policies.

We often show text/image advertisements from advertising partners like Google Adsense. These sites load their scripts on our site to show customized advertisements. These sites are trustworthy but as we do not have complete control on the third party content, we will not be responsible for any harm caused by them. However, if any issues are reported to us, we will make all of our attempts to stop-publishing ads from such sites. Meanwhile, if you don’t want the ads to be shown on your computer, you can freely use ad blocking tools like Adblock Plus. We care about your freedom and we would never ever force you to see ads posted here.

## How we use collected information?

We may collect and use Users personal information for the following purposes:

  * **To improve  content**  
Information you provide helps us respond to your customer service requests and support needs more efficiently.
  * **To personalize user experience**  
We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our Users as a group use the services and resources provided on our Site.
  * **To improve our Site**  
We may use feedback you provide to improve our products and services.
  * To send periodic emails  
We may use the email address to respond to their inquiries, questions, and/or other requests. If User decides to opt-in to our mailing list, they will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email or User may contact us via our Site.

## How we protect your information

We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our Site.

## Sharing your personal information

We do not sell, trade, or rent Users personal identification information to others. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes outlined above. We may use third party service providers to help us operate our business and the Site or administer activities on our behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys.

## Changes to this privacy policy

We have the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. When we do, we will revise the updated date at the top of this page. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications.

## Contacting us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact us at:

Gaurav Tiwari  
124, Krishi Bhawan, New Delhi 110092, India  
Phone: (+91)-956-580-4301  
Email: gaurav(at)gauravtiwari.org
